Guide to the Reagan inauguration miscellany,1981-1995.
Reagan inauguration miscellany,1981-1995.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reagan inauguration miscellany, 1981-1995.
3899
Alan Henry Haeberle, 1950-
.4 cubic ft.
Tickets, passes, invitations, programs, parking signs, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Items related to the inauguration of Ronald Reagan as President and George Bush as Vice President.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University.
Class of 1972.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Items related to the inauguration of Ronald Reagan as President and George Bush as Vice President include tickets, passes, and invitations to inauguration ceremonies and activities; programs; parking signs; photographs; pro-Equal Rights Amendment items; brochures of commemorative items; and religious tracts and magazines.
Also, clippings and articles concerning various Cornell alumni.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Haeberle, Alan Henry, 1950-; Bush, George, b.1924; Reagan, Ronald --Inauguration.
Subjects:
Inauguration Day.; Presidents--United States--Inauguration.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photoprints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Postcard publicizing ERA demonstrations at Inauguration (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Paper pennants, green on white "ERA-YES" one flat, folded in half; (one loosely rolled on stick, in Box 2) (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Paper sticker with adhesive backing, 2-3/4" sq. green circle on square white background, white letter in circle "ERA/YES" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Handouts publicizing ERA activities during Inauguration (2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reception for George Bush at Museum of American Histroy (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Souvenir programs, 8-1/2" x 11", 6 pages, plus front and back cover, front cover embossed in gold with Inaugural seal and "George Bush;" stapled gold cord at binding (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Tickets for recpetion, #'s 0597, 0598, pink with blue and red printing, location originally printed as "Smithsonian Museum of Natural History" - "Natural" crossed out, "American" inserted by hand in felt-tip pen (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Paper napkins from reception, gold printing "Presidential Inauguration," " 1981" and Inaugural seal (3) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Program for concert by The American Boychoir, at the Kennedy Center, Jan. 19, 1981, for the Distinguished Ladies Reception, 10" x 4-1/4" (somewhat soiled) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pamphlets put out by the Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  1. Schedule of Events, Jan. 17-20, 1981, with places of interest, information on Hospitality Booths, shuttle buses, etc.
  2. Inaugural Tape Library, where to call for information about inaugural events
- Envelopes from Presidential Inaugural Committee, one with official meter postmark (2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Programs to "Outdoor Band Concert/The Afternoon of/ Jan. 20, 1981/U.S. Capitol, West Front" (4) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Sheet music for "Thumbs Up, America!" Inaugural theme song, by J. William Middendorf II and Sammy Cahn with insert, reprint from Washington Post, Jan. 13, 1981" 'Thumbs Up': A Cahn-Do Anthem..." (2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1981 Inaugural Program, blue cover with 50 stars in silver, Inaugural seal in gold, 24 pages (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Ticket to South Standing Room Area Capitol Grounds for 1981 Inauguration ceremonies, yellow (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Blue Ticket for parade reviewing stand in front of the District Building on Pennsylvania Avenue, and two place cards from the grandstand indicating where various individuals were to stand (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pamphlets and handouts from museums (Box 1, Folder 4)
- List of "Inaugural Festivities at the Museums of the Smithsonian Institute and other cultural centers... Jan 16-20, 1981" (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "American Art through 40 Presidencies" National Gallery of Art (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Calendar of Events, Jan. 1981, National Gallery of Art (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Calendar of Events in the Library of Congress, Jan. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Various printed and photocopied floorplans and maps showing seating sections for inaugural ceremonies, plus location of press areas and camera positions both on Capitol grounds and inside Capitol builing (5 sheets) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photocopy sheet which was attached to police barricades around the Capitol grounds during Inauguration ceremonies. "By Order of the Capitol Police Board" signed by Sergeants at Arms of U.S. House and Senate and Architect of the Capitol (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Inauguration Rundown." "Final" probably from CBA, script for television coverage of Inauguration, detailed instructions of when to switch to which reporter/camera/loctaion, with commercial breaks, etc. from 10:00:00 am to 1:59:50 pm. 6 pages, legal size photocopies stapled, soiled on first and last pages (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Capitol Poor Camera Positions and Capitol Spotter Positions, instructions for camera and audio positions inside and outside Capitol building during and after Inauguration. 5 pages, photocopied, staples, most pages torn, folded, soiled (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photocopy of letter from George M. White, Architect of the Capitol, to James M. Powell, Chief, U.S. Capitol Police, requesting passes to the Capitol grounds during the Inaugural ceremonies for 15 employees on White's staff, folded and soiled (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photocopy Inaugural Fact Sheet from Presidential Inaugural Committee regarding tickets, seating, parking, etc. during the Inauguration (2) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photocopy of memorandum to all employees of National Park Service, National Capitol Region, regarding Jan. 20, 1981, as a legal holiday (3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Installation instructions for Samsonite chairs used on the Capitol grounds for seating during the Inaugural ceremonies (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Order blank and fact sheet for Inaugural Breakfast sponsored by the Minnesota Republican Delegation, from Senator Rudy Boschwitz (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "PIC" indicates items offered by the Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Handout for souvenirs, and other solicitations (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PIC Inaugural Commemoratives, 16 pages, glossy paper, stapled, 5-1/4" x 8-1/2", full color illustrations (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PIC Inaugural jewelry, press release, 1 sheet, 8-1/2" x 11" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PIC Inaugural jewelry, illustrations, 1 sheet, 8-1/2" x 14" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PIC Inaugural jewelry, order sheet, 1 sheet, blue paper, 5-1/4" x 8-1/2" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PIC "Reproductions of American Paintings" printed on card stock, 6" x 9', folded in half (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PIC Inaugural license plates, pamphlet foldout, printed red and blue on white (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Help Save Ronald Reagan's Boyhood Home" Pamphlet from Ronald Reagan Fund, Dixon, Illinois (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Reagan Collectables" buisness card from V.I.P. Store, Dixon, Illinois (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "The Washington Post Inaugural Editions, Jan. 19-21, 1981" order form, 3-1/2" x 8" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "A Tribute to President Ronald Reagan." Reservation form for "limited edition Presidential Portrait Print" from William Allerton and Associates, New Orlenas, LA, 8-1/2" x 11" (3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Handout, legal size photocopy "To all vendors" from Montco Graphics, a manufacturer of buttons, stickers and other commemorative items, offering "Instant service for very special events of the normal supply" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Religious and political handouts (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Inaugural Souvenir 1981 " from Washington Bible College (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "The Future is Here" sponsored by the New Life Evangelical Church (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Are You Ready for the Judgement Day?" from World Wide Tract Ministry (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Please Chant Hare Krishna...And Your Life Will Be Sublime" from the Hare Krishna Center, Potomac, MD. (2). These handouts were stapled to small bags of popcorn which were given out by Hare Krishna devotees to people in the crowds (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "The Master Plan for America" from Living Waters Branch, Bellmead, Texas 76705 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Wake up America...Separate Church and State" from Universal Publishing, Waco, Texas 76705 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Bayside, 'The Lourders of America'" from Our Lady of Roses Shrine, Bayside, NY (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Back to Godhead, Vol. 15, No. 11, the magazine of the Hare Krishna Movement (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Handout against nuclear power from the Greater Harrisburg Labor Committee for Safe Energy and Full Employment (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Official Inaugural Parody Program by the National Association of College Humor Magazines, 20 pages with glossy cover (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Box 1 also contains plastic bag of shell fragments from fireworks display in front of the Smithsoniam Institute (The Castle) on the mall, evening of Jan. 20, 1981. Discarded per B. Golding, May 1984 (Box 1)
- Oversize Item: "Emergency/No/Parking midnight Jan. 19-midnight Jan. 20, 1981," 11" x 17", posted on a telephone pole in the 3300 block of M Street, N.W. (Box 1)
- Oversize Items: "No/Parking/After/7 pm/ Jan. 19, 1981," posted in the area of the Capitol, 2 copies, 12" x 18" (Box 1)
- Oversize Item: "Parade Assembly/Area/No Admittance," sign from fence put up around the Mall, 10" x 24" (Box 1)
- Oversize Items: 2 signs, "A" and "B," which marked areas for marching groups to assemble before the parade, 12" x 18" (Box 1)
- Oversize Item: Large paper bag with handles, white with red and blue printing, "Reagan-Bush in 1980," "It's in the Bag" (Box 1)
- Souvenir buttons sold by street vendors (Box 2)
  1. 3-1/2" diameter, red, white, and blue writing around edge, "Inauguration, Jan. 20, 1981," "Reagan-Bush," "President--Vice-President," between photos of Regan and Bush in center
  2. 2-1/4" diameter, smaller version of above
  3. 1-3/4" diameter, color photo of Reagan and the White House, organe scroll of top "Inauguration Day," " Jan. 20, 1981" beneath White House "Ronald Reagan," "Our 40th President"
- American Flag printed on plastic 8" x 11-1/2" (Box 2)
- Metal button with pin, 2-1/4" diameter, white on green "ERA/YES" (Box 2)
- Plastic cups from reception, approximately 3" high, printed with Inaugural seal (2) (Box 2)
- Cardboard cover for box which held souvenir medallion given to all who attended reception. 3-1/4' x 2-1/4" x 1/2", dark blue with gold seal "Vice-President of the United States." Inside cover is printed "Medallic Art Co./Danbury, CT." Also, small wooden stand used to display medallion. (Medallion not available) (Box 2)